<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam Ott</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Adam Ott</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Combined Half No-Hitters</title>
      <link>/blog/combined-half-no-hitters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/combined-half-no-hitters/</guid>
      <description>In August 2020 on Episode 1580 of “Effectively Wild”, there was a discussion about “Combined Half No-Hitters”, where neither team allows a hit through 4.5 innings, leading to 9 total half-innings without a hit. I did the queries in my Retrosheet database to find a list of every combined half no-hitter.
To look this up, I first read in attached my R session to my PostgreSQL database using the “dbcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian Approach to Catcher Framing</title>
      <link>/blog/a-bayesian-approach-to-catcher-framing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/a-bayesian-approach-to-catcher-framing/</guid>
      <description>In baseball, although the most important factor in whether a pitch is called a strike or not is the location of the pitch, umpires and catchers also have some effect. Some catchers are better at ``framing&#34; a pitch, presenting it to look like it was thrown in the strike zone. Understanding which catchers are good at framing can help teams know which catchers to attempt to sign or trade for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Consecutive Years with a New Starter on Opening Day</title>
      <link>/blog/most-consecutive-years-with-a-new-starter-on-opening-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/most-consecutive-years-with-a-new-starter-on-opening-day/</guid>
      <description>Throughout 2020, I have helped answer baseball research questions for the FanGraphs podcast “Effectively Wild.” Every couple of weeks, one of the hosts will reach out to be asking if I can find the answer to a baseball history question for a segment known as a “Stat Blast.” To answer the questions, I have largely used two databases: a Retrosheet database I have on my own laptop (set up using a tutorial from Bill Petti at https://billpetti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a Statistics Master&amp;rsquo;s student at Brigham Young University. I enjoy sports, singing, and spending time with my family.
I have previously interned as an Analyst at Energy Exemplar and a Data Scientist at UnitedHealth Group. Currently, I do research and work as a teaching assistant at BYU. I have also done research for &amp;ldquo;Effectively Wild&amp;rdquo;, a FanGraphs baseball podcast.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
